<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>meta on Aidan Murray</title><link>https://thattakashi.github.io/main-portfolio/tags/meta/</link><description>Recent content in meta on Aidan Murray</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thattakashi.github.io/main-portfolio/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Arcadia Studios</title><link>https://thattakashi.github.io/main-portfolio/p/arcadia-studios/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thattakashi.github.io/main-portfolio/p/arcadia-studios/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://thattakashi.github.io/main-portfolio/p/arcadia-studios/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Arcadia Studios" />&lt;p>Arcadia studios is a game studio that specializes in the design and creation of multiple types of video game. The designs for their brand take from both modern minimalism as well as traditional Japanese styles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arcadia Studios takes from both minimalist and Japanese styles as stated before and strives to deliver amazing experiences both in their games as well as their other public spaces. Their website designs for example experiment with different ideas for unique site navigation rather than sticking with the tried and true navigation bar design. This allows for more creative designs that are not as limited by traditional designs while still following web standard guidelines for UI and UX.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blinding Nights</title><link>https://thattakashi.github.io/main-portfolio/p/blinding-nights/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thattakashi.github.io/main-portfolio/p/blinding-nights/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://thattakashi.github.io/main-portfolio/p/blinding-nights/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Blinding Nights" />&lt;p>Blinding Nights is an up and coming game from Arcadia Studios. It is an old school text-based game that takes place entirely inside of a terminal. The game has next to no graphics in game, and these kinds of games usually don’t have very well designed websites, ads, etc. I was tasked with designing the website and other graphical assets such as a logo to use as the games official material.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>https://thattakashi.github.io/main-portfolio/p/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thattakashi.github.io/main-portfolio/p/hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://thattakashi.github.io/main-portfolio/p/hello-world/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Hello World!" />&lt;p>Welcome, dear readers, to a world where creativity knows no bounds and imagination takes flight. Today, we embark on an exciting journey through the heart and soul of design—an odyssey that will illuminate the artistry, innovation, and passion that fuel the creative process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My name is Aidan, and I am thrilled to be your guide on this immersive exploration of my design portfolio. Over the years, I have had the privilege of crafting visual stories, shaping brand identities, and bringing dreams to life through the power of design. Now, I invite you to step into my creative universe and witness the magic firsthand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Design, to me, is more than just a profession; it’s a way of life. It’s about channeling emotions, concepts, and ideas into tangible, visual expressions that resonate with people. It’s about fusing functionality with aesthetics, and it’s about pushing the boundaries of what’s possible. In this blog, I’ll be sharing not just the finished pieces, but also the stories, inspirations, and processes that breathe life into each creation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll journey together through a diverse array of projects—from logo designs that tell the essence of a brand in a single glance to digital illustrations that transport you to far-off realms of wonder and whimsy. Along the way, you’ll discover the techniques, tools, and strategies that underpin effective design, all while gaining insights into the creative mind at work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this blog is not just about me; it’s about us—the design community. I welcome your thoughts, questions, and ideas as we embark on this journey together. Your feedback and engagement will help us learn and grow, fostering a vibrant exchange of ideas that fuels innovation and sparks inspiration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, whether you’re a fellow designer seeking fresh perspectives, a business owner looking to elevate your brand, or simply an art enthusiast with an appreciation for the beautiful and thought-provoking, there’s a place for you here. Together, we’ll explore the boundless possibilities that design offers and celebrate the ever-evolving tapestry of creativity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Get ready to be inspired, enlightened, and perhaps even challenged as we dive headfirst into the world of design. Thank you for joining me on this adventure—it’s going to be an exhilarating ride!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stay tuned for our first deep dive into a captivating design project, coming soon. Until then, remember: in the world of design, every pixel, line, and stroke has a story to tell, and I can’t wait to share them with you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let the journey begin!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aidan Murray (Takashi)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>