<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web-design on Aidan Murray</title><link>https://thattakashi.github.io/main-portfolio/categories/web-design/</link><description>Recent content in Web-design on Aidan Murray</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://thattakashi.github.io/main-portfolio/categories/web-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to design better websites</title><link>https://thattakashi.github.io/main-portfolio/p/web-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thattakashi.github.io/main-portfolio/p/web-design/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://thattakashi.github.io/main-portfolio/p/web-design/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How to design better websites" />&lt;p>In the ever-evolving world of web design, two key elements reign supreme: contrast and white space. These seemingly simple design principles possess the extraordinary power to transform ordinary websites into extraordinary experiences. Join us on a journey through the art and science of contrast and white space, and discover how designers can elevate their website creations to new heights.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-dance-of-contrast">The Dance of Contrast&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Contrast is the yin to the yang of design. It’s the magic wand that brings focus, clarity, and impact to your web pages. Here’s how you can wield it effectively:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Typography Brilliance:&lt;/strong> Start by choosing contrasting typefaces for your headings and body text. This not only enhances readability but also adds personality to your design.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Color Play:&lt;/strong> Mastering the use of color contrast is pivotal. Vibrant buttons against a muted background, for instance, can guide users’ attention and encourage action.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Image Magic:&lt;/strong> Use contrasting imagery to create visual interest. A striking image juxtaposed with a subtle background can tell a compelling story.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Hierarchy Hacks:&lt;/strong> Prioritize information with contrast. Make headlines bolder, buttons brighter, and important content more prominent.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Accessibility Focus:&lt;/strong> Pay attention to accessibility standards. High contrast between text and background ensures that your content is readable for all users.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="embracing-the-serenity-of-white-space">Embracing the Serenity of White Space&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>White space, often referred to as “negative space,” is the breathing room in your design. It’s the canvas upon which your content shines. Here’s how you can harness its power:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Simplicity Sells:&lt;/strong> Keep it clean and uncluttered. White space fosters a sense of elegance and sophistication.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Focus on Content:&lt;/strong> Give your content room to breathe. Well-spaced paragraphs and sections make reading a pleasure.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Visual Balance:&lt;/strong> White space helps in achieving visual equilibrium. It can guide the eye, ensuring that users absorb the message as intended.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mobile Responsiveness:&lt;/strong> Embrace responsive design with white space. It allows for comfortable navigation on various screen sizes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Brand Elevation:&lt;/strong> White space can be used strategically to draw attention to your logo and branding elements, reinforcing your brand identity.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="harmony-in-action">Harmony in Action&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now, let’s see these principles in action. Imagine a sleek e-commerce site selling high-end watches. The use of bold, dark typography for product names creates contrast against a light, minimalist background. High-resolution images of the watches pop against the serene white space, allowing shoppers to focus on the exquisite details. The “Shop Now” button stands out with its vibrant color, enticing users to take action.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By employing the dynamic duo of contrast and white space, this website not only captures attention but also provides a delightful user experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In conclusion, as designers, we hold the keys to creating visually captivating and user-friendly websites. By harnessing the power of contrast and white space, we can sculpt digital landscapes that not only look fantastic but also serve their intended purpose seamlessly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Remember, it’s not about adding more; it’s about crafting purposeful designs that communicate effectively. So, whether you’re redesigning a personal blog, revamping an e-commerce site, or creating a portfolio, let contrast and white space be your guiding stars on the path to design excellence. The results will speak for themselves: websites that engage, inspire, and leave a lasting impression.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Until next time&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aidan Murray (Takashi)&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Photo by &lt;a class="link" href="https://unsplash.com/@pawel_czerwinski" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Pawel Czerwinski&lt;/a> on &lt;a class="link" href="https://unsplash.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Unsplash&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>